lexialearning.com 2019-12-16

# Privacy Policy | Lexia Learning

#### Lexia Website Properties Privacy Policy

Lexia Learning Systems LLC, [a Rosetta Stone Company](https://www.rosettastone.com/lp/about/) (“Lexia”) is the developer of the Lexia® technology-based learning solutions. We take the privacy of our customers seriously. We are committed to safeguarding your privacy while providing a personalized and valuable service.

**Overview**

This Privacy Policy explains the data processing practices of Lexia and the information collection and use of your personal information from our Websites and in off-line sales and marketing activities. It also describes how Lexia shares and secures your personal information, as well as your choices regarding the use, access and correction of your personal information. For our privacy policies concerning the collection and use of personal information collected within and through use of our online subscription products and related services, including the website [www.mylexia.com](http://www.mylexia.com/), and the MyLexia mobile application, please refer to our [Application Data Privacy Policy](https://www.lexialearning.com/privacy). If you have any requests concerning your personal information or any questions about these practices please contact our Privacy Officer by e-mail at [privacy@lexialearning.com](mailto:privacy@lexialearning.com). We encourage you to periodically review this privacy policy as it may change at any time at our sole discretion. Our site contains links to third party sites, which are not subject to this privacy policy. Lexia does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices or content on these sites. We recommend that you read the privacy policy of any such sites that you visit. Information provided by you may be requested from one of our websites or those of our affiliates under the Lexia, Rosetta Stone or Rosetta World brand names, or from one of our reputable co-marketing partner sites that represent our brands on their own websites under their company and/or brand name. In the event that you provide us with personal information for the purposes of free registration and you later make a purchase, whether directly from us or facilitated by one of our e-commerce partners, we will collect and use your personal information according to our stated policies that are posted and available for your review at the time of purchase.

###### **Information Collected**

Personal information is collected by Lexia. We collect personal information about you (your “Data”) through:

  * The use of inquiry and registration forms.
  * The purchase process when you buy any of our products or services
  * The provision of your details to us either online or offline

The elements of your Data that we collect may include:

  * Name
  * Job title
  * Company name
  * Home, shipping and billing addresses, phone and fax number
  * Mobile telephone number
  * E-mail address
  * IP address and browser information
  * Payment details such as credit card information
  * Market research data such as customer usage patterns  

###### **Use and Disclosure of Personal Information**

We use your Data for purposes which may include:

  * Providing our customers with a personalized service and support.
  * Engaging in transactions and communications with our customers.
  * Processing orders, registrations and inquiries.
  * Conducting market research and surveys.
  * Running competitions.
  * Measuring interest in and improving our website, products, and services.
  * Providing you with information about products and services we offer. You may stop the delivery of marketing emails by following the instructions accompanying a particular communication or by contacting us at [privacy@lexialearning.com](mailto:privacy@lexialearning.com).
  * Resolving disputes, collecting fees, and troubleshooting problems.

We use the information you provide when placing an order to complete that order and to service your account. We do not share this information with outside parties except: 1. to the extent necessary to complete that order or to provide services where the outside party is acting on our behalf and has no independent right to use the information we provide (e.g., third-party shipping, business analytics, or customer support ); or 2. to successors in title to our business; or 3. in accordance with legal and regulatory requirements; or 4. as necessary, in Lexia’s sole discretion, to protect the perceived rights, safety and property of Lexia, users of our websites, and the public.  

###### **Sharing with Service Providers**

We may share your information with third parties who provide services on our behalf to help with our business activities.  These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

These services may include:

  * Fulfilling and verifying product and service orders and delivering
  * Payment processing
  * Providing customer service
  * Sending marketing communications
  * Fulfilling subscription services
  * Conducting research and analysis
  * Providing cloud computing infrastructure and hosting
  * Providing product and service support, maintenance and improvement
  * Fulfilling obligations required by law, regulation or contract  

###### **Legal Notice**

We may also disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or other legal process, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.

If Lexia Learning Systems LLC is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website, of any change in ownership, uses of your personal information, and choices you may have regarding your personal information. We may also disclose your personal information to any other third party with your prior consent.

Other than as set out above, you will be notified when personal information about you will be shared with third parties, and you will have an opportunity to choose not to have us share such information.

We also use information in aggregate form:

  * To build up marketing profiles
  * To aid strategic development
  * To audit usage of the site  

###### **Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Devices**

We and our partners use cookies or similar tracking technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service.

We do not use any tracking devices to track your usage of the Internet on other sites not operated by Lexia. If you are a registered user this may include your name and email address for verification purposes.

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the site.

We also use information from cookies for purposes, which may include:

  * Identifying returning users and registrants
  * Enabling users to move more easily around our site
  * Tracking how our users use of our site to better develop our sites in accordance with user requirements
  * Building up a demographic profile of our site users

If you do not want to help us learn how to improve our site, products, offers and marketing strategy, you may choose to set your Web browser to not accept cookies. Further information on how to prevent cookies from being stored on your computer can be found on [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) under the ‘manage cookies’ section. Alternatively, go to the help menu within your Internet browser.

From time to time we may permit third party companies to set cookies on Lexia Websites for purposes which may include market research, revenue tracking or to improve functionality of the site.

We may place or recognize technology on your browser or device when you visit our Sites for purposes of serving you targeted advertising (also referred to as "online behavioral advertising").  We also work with third party advertising companies who place their own cookies or similar technology on your browser or device when you visit our Sites and other websites to serve customized advertisements to you as you browse the Internet. As noted above, you can set your device or browser to accept or reject most cookies, or at least notify you in most situations that the technology is offered. As an additional step, these advertising companies may participate in one of the following self-regulatory programs for online behavioral advertising, with corresponding user opt-outs:

  * Networking Advertising Initiative (<http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>) (US Only)
  * Digital Advertising Alliance (<http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>) (US Only)
  * European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance (<http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>) (EU Only)
  * Digital Advertising Alliance - Canada (<http://youradchoices.ca/choices>) (Canada Only)
  * DAA App Choices Mobile App (Mobile Devices Only) - For mobile devices (e.g., smartphone, tablets), you may consider downloading the DAA AppChoices Mobile App to manage such technology.
  * TRUSTe Opt-out tool – USA (<http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/>)

Please note that even if you reject such technology, you may continue to receive advertisements, but the advertisements will not be tailored to your browsing activities and interests.  

###### **Email or Newsletter Preferences**

You may sign-up to receive email or newsletter or other communications from us.  If you would like to discontinue receiving this information, you may update your email preferences by using the “Unsubscribe” link found in emails we send to you or at your member profile on our website or by contacting us at privacy@lexialearning.com.

###### **Security Policy**

Lexia has appropriate measures in place to help ensure that our users’ Data is protected against unauthorized access or use, alteration, unlawful or accidental destruction and accidental loss. Although we make reasonable efforts to protect your Personal Information from loss, misuse, or alteration by third parties, you should be aware that there is always some risk involved in transmitting information over the Internet. There is also some risk that thieves could find a way to thwart our security systems. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at [privacy@lexialearning.com](mailto:privacy@lexialearning.com).

###### **Transfer of Data**

The Internet is a global environment. Websites, software, services and programs delivered and accessed through the Internet necessarily involve the transmission and processing of personal data, sometimes on an international basis, depending, for example, on where the user is located. When personal information is provided to Lexia through the Websites, the information will be processed from and stored on servers located in the United States and globally, and by using the Websites, you acknowledge and give Lexia authorization to such transfer, processing and storage.

Lexia participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Lexia is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, respectively, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>.

Lexia is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. We comply with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Lexia is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>, you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.  

###### **Access to Data and Contact Info**

Upon request,  Lexia will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You may access, correct, or request deletion of your personal information by contacting us. We will respond to your requests within a reasonable timeframe.

Where required by applicable law, and notably by the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) for residents of the UK and European Union, you have the right to obtain confirmation of the existence of certain Personal Data relating to you, to verify its content, origin, and accuracy, as well as the right to access, review, port, delete, or to block or withdraw consent to the processing of certain Personal Data (without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal), by contacting us as detailed below.   **In particular, you have the right to object to our use of Personal Data for any direct marketing and in certain other situations at any time.   **Please note that certain Personal Data may be retained as required or permitted by applicable law. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding your privacy, please contact us by contacting the Privacy Officer at [privacy@lexialearning.com](mailto:privacy@lexialearning.com) or writing to:

Privacy Officer  
Lexia Learning Systems LLC  
300 Baker Avenue, Suite 320  
Concord Massachusetts 01742  
Email: [privacy@lexialearning.com](mailto:privacy@lexialearning.com)  
Phone: (978) 405-6200

If you are a resident of the UK or European Union with questions regarding your rights in Personal Data under GDPR, please contact the Lexia Learning Data Protection Officer, Sofia Simoes, by email at [DPO@lexialearning.com](mailto:DPO@lexialearning.com).

We may charge the allowable fee under applicable law for provision of this information. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. Please note that additional information may be required to confirm and enable us to assist with your request.  The timeframe to address the request may vary depending on the nature of the request, however, we will endeavor to address the request as promptly as possible, typically within thirty (30) days and as may be required by law.

**Data Retention**

We may retain your personal information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

###### **Children Under 13**

We do not intentionally collect any information on children under 13 years of age from our Websites. We will undertake to delete any details of such users where a parent or guardian has notified us that any such details have been obtained.

This policy is effective May 25, 2018. From time to time we may make changes to this privacy policy to reflect any changes to our privacy practices in accordance with changes in legislation, best practice or website enhancements. We will notify you about material changes to this privacy policy by sending a notice to the email address you provided to us or by placing a prominent notice in this section on our website.
